[
  {
    "period": ["Jan 2011", "May 2012"],
    "type": "personal",
    "title": "MapleBR Private Server",
    "subtitle": "",
    "learnings": "A good way to learn how to code is by testing things made by others",
    "country": "üáßüá∑",
    "where": "Home",
    "public": "Friends",
    "problem": "I needed to practice what I've studied at the University so I started to learn by reading and running open source codes from the internet.",
    "solution": "I built a custom MapleStory private server for testing and learning purposes. I used to code in Java for backend (hosted on a Windows Server 2008), PHP and MySQL to create the page for people to signup. You can see my first page if you read the 3-3-3 Principle.",
    "stacks": ["java", "php", "mysql", "html", "css"],
    "cover": {},
    "action": {
      "label": "",
      "url": ""
    },
    "label": "maplestory"
  },
  {
    "period": ["Jul 2013", "May 2018"],
    "type": "job",
    "title": "SIGUP - System for Public Expenses Data Management",
    "subtitle": "Departamento de √Åguas e Energia El√©trica",
    "learnings": "You can find how to improve a system by observing final user's daily work",
    "country": "üáßüá∑",
    "where": "DAEE",
    "public": "Public Servants and Directors",
    "problem": "Public Expenses Data were all managed by EXCEL spreadsheets, turning it difficult to be maintained and shared.",
    "solution": "I suggested the team to build a centralized database for data management in PHP and MySQL. We researched, prototyped, developed our solution translating spreadsheets and graphics into a centralized dashboard with charts (Google Charts API). The results were an economy of R$200.000 (approx. U$50.000 at that time) in public expenses in 6 years.",
    "stacks": ["php", "mysql", "html", "css", "jquery", "google-charts"],
    "cover": {},
    "action": {
      "label": "",
      "url": ""
    },
    "label": "sigup"
  },
  {
    "period": ["Feb", "2016"],
    "type": "volunteer",
    "title": "Bingo Screen for Matsuri Events",
    "subtitle": "",
    "learnings": "Anything can be used for years if it solves a problem. Even if it's a Web page",
    "country": "üáßüá∑",
    "where": "Hokkaido Association",
    "public": "Events Staff",
    "problem": "We always used a whiteboard to display Bingo Game numbers on our Matsuri Events",
    "solution": "I built a simple SPA in HTML and JQuery to display bingo numbers for our events. It needed to display big-sized numbers because of the elder public. We kept using it at every Matsuri that had bingo prizes. You can try it as well clicking on the link below!",
    "stacks": ["html", "css", "jquery", "bootstrap", "git"],
    "cover": {},
    "action": {
      "label": "Use it for free ",
      "url": "https://gtoshinakano.github.io/bingo-screen/"
    },
    "label": "bingo"
  },
  {
    "period": ["Jun", "2016"],
    "type": "job",
    "title": "Automatic Public Expenses Bills Email Sender",
    "subtitle": "Departamento de √Åguas e Energia El√©trica",
    "learnings": "Everyone has a browser in their pockets so we can reach anyone with JS",
    "country": "üáßüá∑",
    "where": "DAEE",
    "public": "Accounting Dept.",
    "problem": "The public expenses bills from 50+ locations were sent to a centralized building. We needed to send the right bills to the right places by e-mail.",
    "solution": "I built a simple tool in NodeJS to help my colleagues send their emails.",
    "stacks": ["nodejs", "javascript", "nodemailer", "git"],
    "cover": {},
    "action": {
      "label": "",
      "url": ""
    },
    "label": "mailer"
  },
  {
    "period": ["Jul 2019", "Out 2019"],
    "type": "volunteer",
    "title": "Event Cashier Manager with Barcode Reader",
    "subtitle": "",
    "learnings": "Sometimes, the solution needs to do only one thing better than the others.",
    "country": "üáßüá∑",
    "where": "Hokkaido Association",
    "public": "Events Staff",
    "problem": "We imported products from Hokkaido and needed a free solution to manage products, stocks and orders for our Bussanten event.",
    "solution": "Using Cloud Firestore as Backend, it was easy to create a system that registers products, orders and only other necessary info for that occasion. I researched, modeled data structure and built the system using ReactJS and Firebase BaaS.",
    "stacks": ["reactjs", "semantic-ui", "firebase"],
    "cover": {},
    "action": {
      "label": "",
      "url": ""
    },
    "label": "cashier"
  },
  {
    "period": ["Nov 2019", "Mar 2020"],
    "type": "job",
    "title": "Admin Dashboard for Startup Operations",
    "subtitle": "Noli Fretes - STARTUP",
    "learnings": "Prototyping and MVPing at the same time made me think: There must be a lot of UI/UX opportunities out there",
    "country": "üáßüá∑",
    "where": "NOLI",
    "public": "Startup Team",
    "problem": "We had a MVP Backend and a mobile APP in production so we needed a functional admin interface",
    "solution": "I researched the needs, sketched the screens and started building the features by priority order. I created the auth system, CRUD interfaces, and a dashboard for tracking trucks with GoogleMaps.",
    "stacks": ["reactjs", "semantic-ui", "firebase", "google-maps", "redux"],
    "cover": {},
    "action": {
      "label": "",
      "url": ""
    },
    "label": "noli"
  },
  {
    "period": ["May 2020", "Jun 2020"],
    "type": "freelance",
    "title": "Financial Management Spreadsheet with Web Interface",
    "subtitle": "",
    "learnings": "How to create a web application, build and host it for free?",
    "country": "üáßüá∑",
    "where": "ALIBER",
    "public": "Feira da Liberdade's Exhibitors Association",
    "problem": "All financial data from the Association were in an Excel Sheet. They needed an easier way to register information and print monthly balances.",
    "solution": "I converted the .XLS sheet into a Google Spreadsheet, served it's data via Google Apps Scripts http request and made this system in ReactJS. It became a complete dashboard for controlling incomes and expenses.",
    "stacks": ["reactjs", "rsuite", "google-spreadsheets", "google-apps-script"],
    "cover": {},
    "action": {
      "label": "",
      "url": ""
    },
    "label": "aliber"
  },
  {
    "period": ["Jun 2020", "Jul 2020"],
    "type": "personal",
    "title": "Personal Financial Dashboard for My Exchange Time in Japan",
    "subtitle": "",
    "learnings": "You can create a habit if you facilitate the behavior to happen more often",
    "country": "üáØüáµ",
    "where": "Tokyo",
    "public": "Me",
    "problem": "Manage daily personal finances during exchange program in Hokkaido.",
    "solution": "During the 14 days of quarantine period, I built a tool to input daily finances data on a Google Sheets. It was an Google Sheet serving data to a SPA in ReactJS. I created the simplest and easiest input form so I could use it on daily basis. I used that simple interface every time I bought something during my exchange program and the results were a full cash control, input anytime/anywhere, and more learnings",
    "stacks": ["reactjs", "semantic-ui", "google-spreadsheets", "google-apps-script"],
    "cover": {},
    "action": {
      "label": "",
      "url": ""
    },
    "label": "jpn-utils"
  },
  {
    "period": ["Ago 2020", "Mar 2021"],
    "type": "personal",
    "title": "Tutorial Blog for ROS and Drone control",
    "subtitle": "",
    "learnings": "Research ROS and Internet Of Things - IoT - in Japan",
    "country": "üáØüáµ",
    "where": "Hokkaido",
    "public": "Robot Operating System - ROS - University Students",
    "problem": "Practice Web development and explaining skills while doing an Exchange Program",
    "solution": "Built a Blog alike tutorial for ROS and Drone control. In order to build it, I was introduced to tools like NextJS, i18n for internationalization, and GSAP for animating elements. It was a test project and I learned a lot about how to dominate the DOM. It was a practice in English writing as well.",
    "stacks": ["reactjs", "nextjs", "styled-components", "gsap", "ros"],
    "cover": {},
    "action": {
      "label": "Visit Guide",
      "url": "https://ros-bebop-research.vercel.app/"
    },
    "label": "ros"
  },
  {
    "period": ["Jun 2021 ", "Jul 2021"],
    "type": "freelance",
    "title": "Ecoid.com.br Institutional Website",
    "subtitle": "",
    "learnings": "The cleaner it is, better for the user",
    "country": "üáßüá∑",
    "where": "Home",
    "public": "Restaurant Owners who works with food delivery",
    "problem": "The client got an opportunity to represent sales from a paper bowls manufacturer and needed a website to start prospecting.",
    "solution": "I built a simple SPA with a cleaner design. It worked fine at the beginning but, a few months later, the client gave up on the business. It was my first time using TailwindCSS and it made CSS styling really fast. It was when I started to use Design and Prototyping tools like Illustrator and XD",
    "stacks": ["reactjs", "nextjs", "tailwind", "google-analytics"],
    "cover": {},
    "action": {
      "label": "See",
      "url": "https://www.ecoid.com.br/"
    },
    "label": "ecoid"
  },
  {
    "period": ["Jun 2021 ", "Jul 2021"],
    "type": "volunteer",
    "title": "Hokkaido Association Ishikari Nabe Event Promotional Landing Page [Page for Mobile]",
    "subtitle": "",
    "learnings": "A good UX makes users stay on your screen and take actions, whatever the action is",
    "country": "üáßüá∑",
    "where": "Hokkaido Association",
    "public": "Hokkaido Association's Events Leads",
    "problem": "It was our first event after one year of covid pandemics and we needed to present a new plate to the public",
    "solution": "I was in charge of making a page to introduce our event to the public. This time I focused on the page interactivity and on SVG animations. We sent the page on Whatsapp groups, and approx. 50% of all conversions came from our page, and the other 50% came directly from whatsapp or personal contact. I learned a lot about getting the audience attention, lead them to an educational content about the product and then, to let them take an action.",
    "stacks": ["reactjs", "nextjs", "styled-components", "tailwind", "google-analytics"],
    "cover": {},
    "action": {
      "label": "See",
      "url": "https://hokkaido-promo.vercel.app/"
    },
    "label": "ishikari"
  },
  {
    "period": ["Oct 2021 ", "Nov 2021"],
    "type": "freelance",
    "title": "Gustavo Amaral's NFT Collection Landing Page",
    "subtitle": "WeDoIT.jp",
    "learnings": "\"It is not necessary to understand everything to be able to use everything\"",
    "country": "üáßüá∑",
    "where": "WeDoIT.jp",
    "public": "Crypto Currencies Investors",
    "problem": "Find a good way to launch an NFT Collection",
    "solution": "We built a landing page for promoting an NFT Collection from an artist friend. We  promoted it compiling information about the artist and his previous works. The challenge here was to translate the artist's style into an animated Webpage.",
    "stacks": ["reactjs", "nextjs", "tailwind", "gsap", "google-analytics"],
    "cover": {},
    "action": {
      "label": "See",
      "url": "https://wedoit.jp/nft/gustavo-amaral/time-and-space?src=toshi"
    },
    "label": "gustavo-amaral"
  },
  {
    "period": ["Jan 2022 ", "Mar 2022"],
    "type": "freelance",
    "title": "Onoda Boeki Internationalized Website and Logo Design",
    "subtitle": "WeDoIT.jp",
    "learnings": "Progression is better than perfection",
    "country": "üáØüáµ",
    "where": "Tokyo",
    "public": "People interested in importing products from Japan to Brazil",
    "problem": "The client needed a website and a logo for his business",
    "solution": "Me and my friend researched, designed and built a single page institutional Website for the company and it's logo as well.",
    "stacks": ["reactjs", "nextjs", "tailwind", "google-analytics"],
    "cover": {},
    "action": {
      "label": "See",
      "url": "https://onodaboeki.co.jp"
    },
    "label": "onoda"
  },
  {
    "period": ["Apr 2022 ", "Today"],
    "type": "personal",
    "title": "This Portfolio and the 3-3-3 Principles For a Better UX",
    "subtitle": "WeDoIT.jp",
    "learnings": "Keep reading to know me better",
    "country": "üáØüáµ",
    "where": "Tokyo",
    "public": "Recruiters, Developers studying UI/UX and future partners",
    "problem": "Expose my experiences in a clear way to explain how I can help in new projects and teams",
    "solution": "This portfolio is a compilation of what I've done and what I've learned in order to be an UI/UX Developer. The 3-3-3 Principles For A Better UX is a guide for you to understand, learn and apply the fundamentals in your next works!",
    "stacks": ["reactjs", "nextjs", "tailwind", "gsap", "google-analytics"],
    "cover": {},
    "action": {
      "label": "This page",
      "url": "https://gtoshinakano.github.io/uiux-profile/"
    },
    "label": "portfolio"
  }
]
